In this video, I'm going to describe a new way of combining a very large number of
在这个视频中  我将描述一种组合大量 神经网络模型
neural network models without having to separately train a very large number of
而无须分别训练大量模型的新方法
models. This is a method called dropout that's
这是一种叫做 “dropout”的方法
recently been very successful in winning competitions.
最近在赢得比赛中获得了很大的成功
For each training case, we randomly omit some of the hidden units.
对于每一个训练实例 我们随机省略了一些 隐结点
So, we end up with a different architecture for each training case.
因此 对于不同的训练案例  我们以 使用不同结构的神经网络而结束
We can think of this as having a different model for every training case.
我们可以把它认为不同的训练案例有 不同的模型
And then, the question is, how could we possibly train a model on only one
然后 问题是我们如何能在只有一种训练案例时 训练一种模型
training case and how could we average all these models together efficiently at test
我们如何能在训练时把这些模型 有效地平均到一起（average together）
time? The answer is that we use a great deal of
答案就是我们需要用大量的 权重共享的策略
weight sharing. I want to start by describing two
我们想以结合
different ways of combining the outputs of multiple models.
多个模型的输出来描述这 两种不同的方法
In a mixture, we combine models by averaging their output probabilities.
在混合模型中 我们通过平均输出概率来 结合模型
So, if model A assigns probabilities of 0.3, 0.2 and 0.5, to three different
所以 如果模型A分配的概率是0.3 0.2 0.5 有三种不同的答案
answers, model B assigns probabilities of 0.1, 0.8 and 0.1, the combined model
模型B分配的概率是 0.1 0.8 0.1
simply assigns the averages of those probabilities.
结合的模型将简单地分配 概率的平均值
A different way of combining models is to use a product of the probabilities. Here,
结合模型的一种不同的方法是用 概率的乘积 这里
we take a geometric mean of the same probabilities.
我们对相同的概率取集合平均值
So, model A and model B again assign the same probabilities as they did before.
所以 像之前一样 模型A和模型B 将又分配相同的概率
But now, what we do is we multiply each pair of probabilities together and then
但是现在 我们是这样做的 把概率 中每一对乘在一起 然后
take the square root. That's the geometric mean and the
取平方根 那是几何平均值
geometric means will generally add up to less than one.
几何平均值通常总和小于1
So, we have to divide by the sum of the geometric means to normalize the
所以 我们必须除以几何平均值的总和 来归一化概率的分布
distribution so that it adds up to one again.
以使它的加和能再一次等于 1
You'll notice that in a product, a small probability output by one model, has veto
你将注意到在一个乘积中 一个模型的小的 概率输出
power over the other models. Now I want to describe an efficient way to
对于其他的模型具有否决权 现在我想描述
average a large number of neural nets that gives us an alternative to doing the
一种平均大量神经网络的有效的方法  该方法能给 我们一种做正确贝叶斯事情的可供替代的方法
correct Bayesian thing. The alternative probably doesn't work
这种可供替代的方法可能没有
quite as well as doing the correct Bayesian thing, but it's much more
像做正确的贝叶斯的事情那么好 但是 它却很实用
practical. So, consider the neural net with one
因此 考虑到含有一个隐藏层的神经网络 如右图所示
hidden layer, shown on the right. Each time we present a training example to
每一次我们展示一个训练的例子时
it, What we're going to do is randomly emit
我们将要做的事随机地以 0.5 的概率
each hidden unit with a probability of 0.5.
以 0.5 的概率省略（emit是否为omit）每一个 隐藏层中的单元
So, we crossed out three of the hidden units here.
所以  这里我们删去隐藏层的三个单元
And we run the example through the net with those hidden units absent.
我们通过缺乏那些隐藏单元的网络 来运行这个实例
What this means is that we're randomly sampling from two to the h architectures,
这意味着我们要从2^H种结构中随机进行采样
where h is the number of hidden units, It's a huge number of architectures.
这里H是隐藏单元的数目 这是 大量的结构体系
Of course, all of these architectures show weights.
当然 所有的这些结构表现的是权重
That ism whenever we use a hidden unit, it's got the same weight as it's got in
那就是说无论何时我们用一个隐藏层单元 它将在其它的结构中获得相同的权重
other architectures. So, we can think of dropout as a form of
所以 我们可以把 "dropout"认为是 一种模型平均值的形式
model averaging. We sample from these two to the h models.
我们从2^H种模型中进行采样
Most of the models, in fact, will never be sampled.
事实上 这些模型中的绝大多数将从不 被采样
And a model of this sampled only gets one training example.
一个模型的采样将仅仅得到一个训练的实例
That's a very extreme form of bagging. The training sets are very different for
那是一种非常极端的包装形式 对于不同模型的 训练集都是不同的
the different models, but they're also very small.
但它们也都很小
The sharing of the weights between all the models means that each model is very
所有这些模型之间的权重共享的策略 意味着每一个模型都被其他的模型
strongly regularized by the others. And this is a much better regularizer than
强烈的正则约束 这是一种
things like L2 or L1 penalties. Those penalties pull the weights toward
比L2范数或L1范数惩罚项更好的正则化矩阵 因子 使权重更加接近于0
zero. By sharing weights with other models, a
通过与其他的模型共享权重
models gets regularized by something that's going to tend to pull the weight
模型获得的正则约束将趋向于 把权重拉近正确的值
towards the correct value. The question still remains what we do with
问题仍然是测试时间我们做什么
test time. So, we could sample many of the
所以 我们能够采样很多结构
architectures, maybe a hundred, and take the geometric mean of the output
可能是一百 然后取输出分布的 几何平均值
distributions. But that would be a lot of work.
但那将是很大的工作量
There's something much simpler we can do. We use all of the hidden units, but we
这是我们能做的很简单的事情 我们 用所有的隐藏层单元
halve their outgoing weights. So, they have the same expected effect as
但是我们有它们的输出权重 所以在采样时 它们实际上有和预期相同的效果
they did when we were sampling. It turns out that using all of the hidden
事实证明用全部隐藏神经元的 一半的输出权重
units with half their outgoing weights, exactly computes the geometric mean that
能准确地计算几何平均值
the predictions that all two to the h models would have used, provided we're
所有2^H个模型已经用到的预测值 假如我们用 softmax 的输出组
using a softmax output group. If we have more than one hidden layer, we
如果我们不仅有一层隐藏层
can simply use drop out at 0.5 in every layer.
我们可以简单地在每一层用 以概率为0.5 的 "dropout"的策略
At test time, we halve all the outgoing weights of hidden units,
在测试时 我们有全部隐含层的输出权重
And that gives us what I call the mean net.
这给了我们我平时所说的 均值的网络
So, we use a net that has all of the units but the weights are halved.
所以 我们用一个有所有单元 但权重减半的网络
When we have multiple hidden layers, this is not exactly the same as averaging lots
当我们有多个隐含层时 这和计算每一个 “dropout”模型是不太一样的
of set per dropout model, but it's a good approximation and it's fast.
但是它是一种好的近似而且 它的速度也很快
We could run lots of stochastic models with dropout, and then average across
我们能用"dropout"的方法运行了很多随机 模型 然后对那些随机模型取平均
those stochastic models. And that would have one advantage over the
这个均值网络将有一个优点
mean net. It would give us an idea of the
在答案中它将给我们一个 不确定性的观点
uncertainty in the answer. What about the input layer?
输入层怎么样?
Well, we can use the same trick there, too.
我们也能很好地在那里使用相同的技巧
We use dropout on the inputs, but we use a higher probability of keeping an input.
我们在输入中使用“dropout”的策略 但我们用较高 的概率保持输入的值
This trick's already in use in a system called denoising autoencoders, developed
这个技巧已经在叫做去噪的自动编码机中 所应用
by Pascal Vincent, Hugo Laracholle and Yoshua Bengio at the University of
该方法是由蒙特利尔大学的 Pascal Vincent, Hugo Laracholle和Yoshua Bengio所研制的
Montreal, and it works very well. So, how well does dropout work?
它取得的效果非常好 "dropout"方法是如何工作的?
Well, the record breaking object recognition net developed by Alex
由Alex Krizhevsky研发的破纪录的目标识别的网络
Krizhevsky would have broken the record even without dropout.
已经打破了记录 即使没有用到"dropout"的策略
But it broke a lot more by using dropout. In general, if you have a deep neural net
但是使用"dropout"的策略能打破的更多一些 通常来讲 如果你有一个深度神经网络
and it's overfitting dropout, it will typically reduce the number errors by
而且它是过度拟合的   "dropout"的策略 将极大地减少错误的数目
quite a lot. I think any net that requires early
我认为任何网络都需要提前终止
stopping in order to prevent it overfitting would do better by using
以防止过度拟合 但是使用"dropout"的方法 能做得更好
dropout. It would, of course, take longer to train and it might mean more hidden
当然 这需要更长的训练时间 也需要对更多的隐含单元取均值
units. If you got a deep neural net and it's not
如果你得到一个深度神经网络并且 它不是过拟合的
overfitting, you should probably be using a bigger one and using dropout, that's
你应该使用更大的网络并且使用 "dropout"的策略
assuming you have enough computational power.
那是假定你有足够的计算能力
There's another way to think about dropout, which is how I originally arrived
这是思考"dropout"策略的另一种方式 这是 我最初想到的方法
at the idea. And you'll see it's a bit related to
你将看到它和混合专家的网络有点相关
mixtures of experts, and what's going wrong when all the experts cooperate,
当所有的专家合作时将出现什么问题
What's preventing specialization? So, if a hidden unit knows which other
什么避免了专门化?  如果一个隐含神经元 知道其他哪几个隐含神经元起作用
hidden units are present, it can co-adapt to the other hidden units on the training
它将会在训练集上相互适应其它的隐含的单元
data. What that means is, the real signal that's
这意味着什么  训练一个隐含的神经元的 真实的信号是
training a hidden unit is, try to fix up the error that's leftover when all the
试着去修复当所有其它的隐含 神经元遗留的错误的说
other hidden units have had their say. That's what's being back propagated to
那是反向传递来训练每一个隐含单元的权重
train the weights of each hidden unit. Now, that's going to cause complex
现在 这将造成在隐含神经元之间的 复杂的相互自适应
co-adaptations between the hidden units. And these are likely to go wrong when
当数据发生变化时将出现什么问题
there's a change in the data. So, a new test data,
因此 一个新的测试数据集
If you rely on a complex co-adaptation to get things right on the training data,
如果你依赖复杂的相互自适应策略 在训练集上得到正确的事情
it's quite likely to not work nearly so well on new test data.
在新的测试集上很可能效果不会非常好
It's like the idea that a big, complex conspiracy involving lots of people is
就像这个观点 一个大的复杂的密谋团体 总会包括一些确定会出错的人
almost certain to go wrong because there's always things you didn't think of.
因为总有一些你没有想到的事情
And if there's a large number of people involved, one of them will behave in an
如果有大量的人被卷入其中 他们中总有人 会表现出意想不到的行为
unexpected way. And then, the others will be doing the
于是其他的人也会做错事
wrong thing. It's much better if you want conspiracies,
如果你想密谋 最好有一些小的 密谋的团体
to have lots of little conspiracies. Then, when unexpected things happen, many
然后 当意外的事情发生时
of the little conspiracies will fail, but some of them will still succeed.
这些小的密谋团体中的很多将失败 但是它们中的一些仍会成功
So, by using dropout, We force a hidden unit to work with
因此 使用"dropout"的策略 我们会迫使 一个隐含的神经元
combinatorially many other sets of hidden units.
与许多其它集合中的隐含的单元组合地工作
And that makes it much more likely to do something that's individually useful
这使它更有可能做对对个案有用的事情
rather than only useful because of the way particular other hidden units are
而不仅仅是有用 由于其他的特别的隐含的单元 与它进行合作
collaborating with it. But it is also going to tend to do
但这也通常趋于去做对个体有用的事情
something that's individually useful and is different from what other hidden units
与其他隐含单元做的事情有一定的区别
do. It needs to be something that's marginally
它需要一些边际效应的事情
useful, given what its co-workers tend to achieve.
鉴于它的合作者通常会实现的事情
And I think this is what's giving nets with dropout, their very good performance.
我想这是有"dropout"的策略的网络有 很好的表现性能的原因